Finding aid for Owen A. Tomlinson papers, 1899-1920
Bentley Historical Library
Owen A. Tomlinson papers
1899-1920
Bentley Historical Library
Tomlinson, Owen A., 1882-
85419 Aa 2; UAm
2 linear feet
1 oversize folder
Officer in the Philippine Constabulary, Ifugao, Mountain Province. Official communications, including orders and promotion and appointment material; biographical sketches of residents of Ifugao Subprovince; printed material; and photographs. The collection also includes "Record Historico. Del Settlement de Quiangan, Sub-Provincia Ifugao, Provincia Montafiosa" by Second Lieutenant Maximo Meimban, P.C.
The collection was the gift of members of the Tomlinson family (donor no. 6400 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Owen A. Tomlinson was an officer in the Philippine Constabulary, Ifugao, Mountain Province in the first two decades of the twentieth century.
Second Lieutenant Maximo Meimban was a Filipino officer and a Pampanga Province native, who served in the constabulary.
The collection includes official constabulary documents, including orders and promotion and appointment material. In addition, there are biographical sketches of residents of Ifugao Subprovince and miscellaneous clippings and printed material. Spanish-language "Record Historico. Del Settlement de Quiangan, Sub-Provincia Ifugao, Provincia Montafiosa" (translated from Spanish as "Historical Record of the Quiangan Settlement, Ifugao Sub-Province, Montafiosa Province") by Lt. Maximo Meimban, describes Ifugao land and villages. Within the Photograph series will be found six albums containing photos of Philippine Constabulary and U.S. Army personnel, and other colonial officials, Philippine people of the Mountain and Nueva Vizcaya provinces including Bontoc, Igorot, and Ifugao people, headhunter ceremony, travel in China, and a visit of Dean C. Worcester to Ifugao.
Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; China -- History -- 1861-1912.; Filipinos.; Headhunters.; Philippines -- History -- 1898-1946.; Soldiers -- American -- Philippines.; China -- History -- Republic, 1912-1949.; Photographs.; Meimban, Maximo.; Philippine Constabulary.; United States. Army.; Worcester, Dean C. (Dean Conant), 1866-1924.
- Constabulary documents
  - 1899-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1906-1910 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1912 (Box 1)
  - 1913-1914 (Box 1)
  - 1915-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917-1920 (Box 1)
- Other materials
  - Biographical sketches of the Subprovince of Ifugao (Box 1)
  - Record Historico. Del Settlement de Quiangan, Sub-Provincia Ifugao, Provincia Montafiosa. Por el Segundo Teniente, M. Meimban, P.C. segun requerido en la Orden Ejecutiva No. 2, Enero 26, de, 1911; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Clippings (Box 1)
  - Printed material (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Photograph albums of Philippine life and constabulary activities, 6 volumes (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous photos (Folder 1)